本字幕由 YYeTs人人影视 修订制作
欢迎爱好者加入我们  www.YYeTs.com
■
字幕来源:  TLF(lulukaola)  后期特效:  @LP_LadiesMan
很久很久以前,
在一个遥远的银河中...
星球大战
第六章
绝地武士归来
天行者卢克回到了他的母星塔图因
试图从大恶棍赫特族的贾巴手中
救出他的朋友  汉·索罗
但是卢克并不知道
帝国正秘密开始建设一个新的武装空间站
其威力比第一颗死星还要强大
一旦它建成
这个终极武器就将决定反抗者的命运
而此时
反抗者们还在为重建星际间的自由而奋斗...
指挥站  这里是ST-321号  通行密码为蓝色
Command station, this is ST-321. Code clearance blue.
我们即将着陆  请解除护盾
We're starting our approach. Deactivate the security shield.
只要我们能确认你们的密码
The security deflector shield will be deactivated...
我们就会解除护盾
when we have confirmation of your code transmission.
准备
Stand by.
你们可以着陆了
You are clear to proceed.
我们准备着陆
We're starting our approach.
告诉指挥官维德勋爵的飞船已经抵达
Inform the commander that Lord Vader's shuttle has arrived.
长官
Sir.
维德勋爵  见到您真是意外之喜  我们深感荣幸
Lord Vader, this is an unexpected pleasure. We're honoured.
你可以省掉这种客套了  指挥官阁下
You may dispense with the pleasantries, Commander.
我来此是监督你们按期办事的
I'm here to put you back on schedule.
我向您保证  维德勋爵  我的人正全力工作
I assure you, Lord Vader, my men are working as fast as they can.
那也许我能找到个新方法让他们更努力
Perhaps I can find new ways to motivate them.
如我所说  整个空间站将如期投入使用
I tell you this station will be operational as planned.
皇帝陛下对局势的评估可没有你这么乐观
The emperor does not share your optimistic appraisal of the situation.
但是他所要求的是不可能的  我需要更多的人
But he asks the impossible. I need more men.
那等他驾临的时候  也许你也能向他这么回奏
Then perhaps you can tell him when he arrives.
- 皇帝陛下会驾临此地? - 完全正确  指挥官阁下...
- The emperor's coming here? - That is correct, Commander...
而且他肯定会对你工作缺乏进展深感不满
and he is most displeased with your apparent lack of progress.
我们将加倍努力
We shall double our efforts.
我希望如此  指挥官阁下  这也是为了你好
I hope so, Commander, for your sake.
皇帝陛下可不会像我一样宽容大度
The emperor is not as forgiving as I am.
我当然担心  你也该担心啊
Of course I'm worried. And you should be too.
兰多·卡尔瑞辛和可怜的楚巴卡不会从这个差劲的地方回来了
Lando Calrissian and poor Chewbacca never returned from this awful place.
别这么肯定
Don't be so sure.
我要是把赫特族的贾巴的事情告诉你一半
If I told you half the things I've heard about this Jabba the Hutt...
你就得短路
you'd probably short-circuit.
R2  你肯定他们就在这吗?
R2, are you sure this is the right place?
我想我还是敲门比较好
I'd better knock, I suppose.
好像这里没什么人  我们回去告诉卢克主人吧
There doesn't seem to be anyone here. Let's go back and tell Master Luke.
天啊!
Goodness gracious me!
我想他们是不会让我们进去的  R2
I don't think they're going to let us in, R2.
我们还是走吧
We'd better go.
R2  等一下
R2, wait.
哦  天啊  R2
Oh, dear. R2.
R2  我坚信我们不该这么冒然闯入的
R2, I really don't think we should rush into all this.
哦  R2!
Oh, R2!
R2  等等我!
R2, wait for me!
你就把卢克主人的口信告诉他们然后我们就走吧!
Just you deliver Master Luke's message and get us out of here.
哦  天啊!
Oh, my!
哦  不!
Oh, no.
哦  天啊!
Oh, my.
我们给你的主人  赫特族的贾巴带来个口信
We bring a message to your master,Jabba the Hutt.
还有一件礼物
And a gift.
什么礼物?
What gift?
他说我们只能告诉贾巴本人
He says that our instructions are to give it only to Jabba himself.
我很抱歉  不过我想他对这种事情从来就是这么固执的
I'm terribly sorry. I'm afraid he's ever so stubborn about these sort of things.
R2  我对此有个不好的预感
R2, I have a bad feeling about this.
早上好
Good morning.
口信  R2  口信呢
The message, R2. The message.
尊贵的阁下  谨致以崇高的敬意
Greetings, Exalted One.
请允许我介绍自己
Allow me to introduce myself.
我是天行者卢克  绝地武士  索罗船长的朋友
I am Luke Skywalker, Jedi knight and friend to Captain Solo.
我知道你是伟大强悍的贾巴...
I know that you are powerful, mighty Jabba...
我也理解你对索罗也一定怒气冲天
and that your anger with Solo must be equally powerful.
我期望阁下可以听听我的建议  看什么可以用来交换索罗的生命
I seek an audience with Your Greatness to bargain for Solo's life.
以您的智慧  我相信我们一定可以找到一个方案
With your wisdom, I'm sure we can work out an arrangement...
对我们都有利
which will be mutually beneficial...
而且可以避免我们之间发生不愉快的冲突
and enable us to avoid any unpleasant confrontation.
为了表示我的善意  我有一份礼物送给您
As a token of my goodwill, I present to you a gift-
就是这两个机器人
these two droids.
他说什么?
What did he say?
他们都很勤劳  会好好替你服务的
Both are hard-working and will serve you well.
这不可能  R2  你肯定放错消息了
This can't be. R2, you're playing the wrong message.
他不是绝地武士
He's no Jedi.
没什么交易好谈的
There will be no bargain.
我们死定了
We're doomed.
我不会放弃我最喜欢的装饰品的
I will not give up my favourite decoration.
我喜欢索罗船长待在这里
I like Captain Solo where he is.
R2  看  索罗船长
R2, look. Captain Solo.
他还在被碳化冷冻着
And he's still frozen in carbonite.
卢克主人到底是怎么回事?
What could possibly have come over Master Luke?
是我做错什么事了吗?
Was it something I did?
他从来没有对我的工作表示什么不满啊
He never expressed any unhappiness with my work.
这太可怕了
How horrid!
不错啊  新货色
Good. New acquisitions.
你是个礼仪机器人  对吧?
You are a protocol droid, are you not?
我是C-3PO...
I am C-3PO-
回答是或不是
Yes or no will do.
那  是的
Well, yes.
你会说多少种语言?
How many languages do you speak?
我可以流利使用超过六百万种交流方式  而且可以...
I am fluent in over six million forms of communication and can readily...
好极了  我们已经好久没有翻译了
Splendid. We have been without an interpreter...
上个礼仪机器人得罪了我们的主人...
since our master got angry with our last protocol droid...
然后被分解了
and disintegrated him.
分解?
Disintegrated?
警卫  这个礼仪机器人可能有用
Guard, this protocol droid might be useful.
给他装上防逃螺栓
Fit him with a restraining bolt...
然后带他去大人的剧场去
and take him back up to His Excellency's main audience chamber.
R2  别离开我!
R2, don't leave me!
你这个坏脾气的小家伙
You're a feisty little one...
你马上就会懂得什么叫尊重了
but you'll soon learn some respect.
我要你去主人的游船那里去
I have need for you on the master's sail barge...
我想你在那里会很合适
and I think you'll fill in nicely.
啊!再表演一次!
Ah! Do that again!
我来领这个伍基族人的赏金
I have come for the bounty on this Wookiee.
哦  不  楚巴卡
Oh, no. Chewbacca.
至少我们抓住了强大的楚巴卡
At last we have the mighty Chewbacca.
我在这里  尊敬的主人
Yes, I am here, Your Worshipfulness.
有何吩咐?
Yes?
光荣的贾巴对你表示欢迎...
The illustrious Jabba bids you welcome...
并很高兴付你二万五千元酬劳
and will gladly pay you the reward of 25,000.
我要五万  一分不能少
I want 50,000. No less.
"五万  一分不能少"
"50,000. No less. "
我说什么了?
What did I say?
伟大的贾巴问为什么他要付五万
The mighty Jabba asks why he must pay 50,000.
因为他带了一个热核引爆器
Because he's holding a thermal detonator.
这个赏金猎人和我一样
This bounty hunter is my kind of scum...
无所畏惧而又富有创新精神
fearless and inventive.
贾巴愿意付三万五
Jabba offers the sum of 35...
我建议你接受
and I do suggest you take it.
他同意了!
He agrees!
先休息一下
Just relax for a moment.
你从碳化冷冻中被解救出来了
You're free of the carbonite.
不过你还有休眠反应
You have hibernation sickness.
- 我看不见 - 你的视力会恢复的
- I can't see. - Your eyesight will return in time.
- 我在哪里? - 贾巴的宫殿
- Where am I? - Jabba's palace.
你是谁?
Who are you?
- 一个爱你的人 - 莉娅
- Someone who loves you. - Leia.
我得救你出去
I gotta get you out of here.
那是什么声音?
What's that?
我听过这个笑声
I know that laugh.
嘿  贾巴
Hey,Jabba.
听我说  贾巴  我正要付给你钱
Look,Jabba, I was just on my way to pay you back.
只是有事耽搁了我一下  这不是我的错
I got a little sidetracked. It's not my fault.
太晚了  索罗
It's too late for that, Solo.
你本来可以是一个很好的走私客的...
You may have been a good smuggler...
但是你现在只能做本莎兽的饲料
but now you're Bantha fodder.
听我说...
Look-
把他带走
Take him away.
贾巴  我会给你三倍的钱
Jabba, I'll pay you triple.
你干嘛要凭白放弃一大笔钱呢  别犯傻
You're throwing away a fortune here. Don't be a fool.
把她带上来
Bring her to me.
我们有强大的朋友
We have powerful friends.
你会后悔这么做的
You're gonna regret this.
我相信
I'm sure.
我看不下去了
I can't bear to watch.
楚伊?（楚巴卡的昵称）
Chewie?
楚伊?是你吗?
Chewie, is that you?
等一下  我看不见
Wait a minute. I can't see, pal.
这怎么回事?
What's going on?
卢克?卢克疯了
Luke? Luke's crazy.
他连自己都照顾不好  还想救别人
He can't even take care of himself, much less rescue anybody.
他成了绝地武士?
A Jedi knight?
我有一阵子和外界没什么联系了
I'm out of it for a little while,
怎么每个人都幻想自己变成伟大人物了
everybody gets delusions of grandeur.
我还好  朋友
I'm all right, pal.
我还好
I'm all right.
我一定要和贾巴谈谈
I must speak with Jabba.
没什么交易好谈的
No bargain.
你现在带我去见贾巴
You will take me to Jabba now.
好好替你的主人服务
You serve your master well.
你会得到丰厚奖赏的
And you will be rewarded.
终于来了  卢克主人终于来救我了
At last! Master Luke's come to rescue me.
主人
Master.
天行者卢克  绝地武士
Luke Skywalker, Jedi knight.
我告诉你不要让他进来的
I told you not to admit him.
我必须要和你谈谈
I must be allowed to speak.
他必须要和你谈谈
He must be allowed to speak.
你这个精神脆弱的笨蛋!
You weak-minded fool!
他只不过用绝地武士那套精神控制的老把戏而已
He's using an old Jedi mind trick.
你会把索罗船长和伍基族的人交给我
You will bring Captain Solo and the Wookiee to me.
你的精神力量对我无效  小子
Your mind powers will not work on me, boy.
没关系...
Nevertheless...
我要带走索罗船长和他的朋友
I'm taking Captain Solo and his friends.
你或者把他们卖给我赚钱  或者我把你干掉
You can either profit by this or be destroyed.
你自己掂量着办  不过我要警告你别低估我的能力
It's your choice, but I warn you not to underestimate my powers.
卢克主人  你正站在...
Master Luke, you're standing on-
没什么交易好谈的  小绝地武士
There will be no bargain, young Jedi.
我会很高兴看到你怎么死掉的
I shall enjoy watching you die.
哦  不!仇恨兽!
Oh, no! The rancor!
把索罗和伍基族的那家伙给我带来
Bring me Solo and the Wookiee.
他们会为这暴行付出代价的
They will all suffer for this outrage.
汉
Han.
- 你还好吗? - 很好  我们又在一起了  对吧?
- Are you all right? - Fine. Together again, huh?
- 我可不想 - 我们现在情况如何?
- Wouldn't miss it. - How are we doin'?
- 还是老样子 - 有那么差吗?
- Same as always. - That bad, huh?
- 莉娅在哪里? - 我在这里
- Where's Leia? - I'm here.
哦  亲爱的
Oh, dear.
尊贵的主人  伟大的赫特族的贾巴...
His High Exaltedness, the great Jabba the Hutt...
已经饬令对你们立即处以死刑
has decreed that you are to be terminated immediately.
很好  我不喜欢长时间的等待
Good. I hate long waits.
因此你们将被带到沙丘海...
You will therefore be taken to the Dune Sea...
投入卡库恩洞穴之中
and cast into the Pit of Carkoon...
那里居住着强大的沙列克
nesting place of the all-powerful Sarlacc.
听起来不算太差
Doesn't sound so bad.
在他肚子里面你们会更明白什么叫做受难和痛苦
In his belly, you will find a new definition of pain and suffering...
因为你们将会在超过1000年中被缓慢消化
as you are slowly digested over 1,000 years.
我又想了一下  让我们这么说吧
On second thought, let's pass on that.
你还是该接受我们的交易  贾巴
You should have bargained,Jabba.
这会是你犯的最后一个错误了
That's the last mistake you'll ever make.
我觉得我的眼睛好多了
I think my eyes are getting better.
以前是一大片黑暗  现在是一大片光明
Instead of a big dark blur, I see a big light blur.
没什么好看的  我曾经住在这里  你知道的
There's nothing to see. I used to live here, you know.
你也要死在这里了  倒是挺合适
You're gonna die here, you know. Convenient.
靠楚伊和兰多近点
Just stick close to Chewie and Lando.
我已经把一切都处理好啦
I've taken care of everything.
好的很
Great.
很快你就学着感激我了
Soon you will learn to appreciate me.
我很抱歉
I'm terribly sorry.
R2  你在这里干嘛?
R2, what are you doing here?
我知道你在这里送饮料  但是这里可危险的很
I can see you're serving drinks, but this place is dangerous.
他们要处决卢克主人了
They're going to execute Master Luke,
如果我们不当心点  我们也得完蛋
and if we're not careful, us too.
我真希望我也能像你那么自信
I wish I had your confidence.
沙列克的祭品们
Victims of the almighty Sarlacc...
尊贵的主人希望你们能死的有尊严
His Excellency hopes that you will die honourably.
不过如果你们之中谁要请求他的宽恕
But should any of you wish to beg for mercy...
伟大的赫特族的贾巴现在将聆听你们的恳求
the great Jabba the Hutt will now listen to your pleas.
3PO  你告诉他那个大混蛋
他不会从我们这里得到这种满足的
he'll get no such pleasure from us!
对吧?
Right?
贾巴  这是你最后的机会了
This is your last chance.
放我们走  不然就去死
Free us or die.
把他带到那里去
Move him into position.
推他进去
Put him in.
小心点  楚伊
Easy, Chewie.
救命!
Help!
楚伊  你被击中了?伤在哪里?
Chewie, you're hit? Where is it?
汉  楚伊!
Han, Chewie!
兰多
Lando.
博巴·费特?
Boba Fett?
博巴·费特?在哪?
Boba Fett? Where?
- 兰多  抓住它! - 再低点!
- Lando, grab it! - Lower it!
我正在努力呢!
I'm trying!
抓住我  楚伊  抓住!
Grab me, Chewie. Grab it!
抓住他  就差一点了  你马上就碰到它了
Grab it. Almost. You almost got it.
轻点
Gently, now.
轻点  抓住我  楚伊
Easy. Hold me, Chewie.
楚伊  给我枪
Chewie, give me the gun.
- 兰多  别动 - 等等!你不是看不见吗!
- Don't move, Lando. - Wait! I thought you were blind!
我现在视力好多了  别动
I can see a lot better. Don't move.
再瞄高点!
A little higher!
楚伊  拉我们上去
Chewie, pull us up.
拉啊  楚伊  拉
Up, Chewie. Up.
我们要离开这里
We gotta get out of here.
别碰我的眼睛!R2  救救我!
Not my eyes! R2, help!
快点  R2!
Quickly, R2!
野兽!
Beast!
去炮那里!
Get the gun!
瞄向甲板
Point it at the deck.
瞄向甲板!
Point it at the deck!
R2  我们去哪里?我可能不能...
R2, where are we going? I couldn't possibly-
过来
Come on.
- 我们离开这里吧  别忘了机器人 - 我们上路了
- Let's go. Don't forget the droids. - We're on our way.
我在舰队这里等你
I'll meet you back at the fleet.
快点  联盟军现在应该已经集合了
Hurry. The Alliance should be assembled by now.
- 我会的 - 卢克  谢谢你
- I will. - Luke, thanks.
谢谢你来救我  我欠你一命
Thanks for coming after me. Now I owe you one.
没错  R2  我们现在去达古巴星系
That's right, R2. We're going to the Dagobah system.
我向一个老友保证要去
I have a promise to keep...
现在我得去实践我的诺言
to an old friend.
平身  我的朋友
Rise, my friend.
死星将如期完成
The Death Star will be completed on schedule.
你干的不错  维德勋爵
You've done well, Lord Vader.
现在我感觉你想继续寻找年轻的天行者
Now I sense you wish to continue your search for young Skywalker.
是的  我的主人
Yes, my master.
耐心点  我的朋友
Patience, my friend.
到时候  他会来找你的
In time, he will seek you out.
等他来的时候  你一定要把他带到我的面前
When he does, you must bring him before me.
他已经变强了
He has grown strong.
只有我们一起才能把他拉到"原力"的黑暗面来
Only together can we turn him to the dark side of the Force.
如您所愿
As you wish.
所有事情都如同我预见的一样进行
Everything is proceeding as I have foreseen.
你那是什么表情
That face you make-
觉得我太老了?
Look I so old to young eyes?
不  当然不是
No, of course not.
我老了
I do.
我确实老了
Yes, I do.
疾病缠身
Sick have I become.
又老又虚弱
Old and weak.
等你九百岁的时候
When 900 years old you reach...
你也好不到哪里去
look as good you will not.
我很快就会休息了
Soon will I rest.
是的  彻底的安息
Yes. Forever sleep.
这是我应得的结局
Earned it I have.
尤达大师  你不能死啊
Master Yoda, you can't die.
尽管我的"原力"很强大...
Strong am I with the Force...
可是我身体已经不行了
but not that strong.
双星即将降临  很快夜晚就要来到
Twilight is upon me, and soon night must fall.
这就是世界之道
That is the way of things...
"原力"之道
the way of the Force.
但是我需要你的帮助
But I need your help.
我来此是要完成我的训练的
I've come back to complete the training.
你不需要什么训练了
No more training do you require.
你需要的你已经都知道了
Already know you that which you need.
那我已经是绝地武士了
Then I am a Jedi.
还不是
Not yet.
还差一件事情
One thing remains-
维德  你必须对抗维德
Vader. You must confront Vader.
那时  只有那时  你才成为一名绝地武士
Then...only then... a Jedi will you be.
而你会对抗他的
And confront him you will.
尤达大师...
Master Yoda...
达斯·维德是我父亲吗?
is Darth Vader my father?
我需要休息
Rest I need.
是的
Yes.
休息
Rest.
尤达  我必须知道
Yoda, I must know.
他是你的父亲
Your father he is.
他告诉你了  对吧?
Told you, did he?
是的
Yes.
真没想到
Unexpected this is.
太不幸了
And unfortunate.
很不幸我知道了事实?
Unfortunate that I know the truth?
不
No.
很不幸你那么早面对他...
Unfortunate that you rushed to face him...
你的训练还没有结束
that incomplete was your training...
对你要承担的重任还没做好准备
that not ready for the burden were you.
对不起
I'm sorry.
记住  绝地武士的力量来自于"原力"
Remember, a Jedi's strength flows from the Force.
但是要小心
But beware.
愤怒  恐惧  好战...
Anger, fear, aggression...
这些都是黑暗的一面
the dark side are they.
一旦你踏上了黑暗之路...
Once you start down the dark path...
你就永远无法回头了
forever will it dominate your destiny.
不要...
Do not-
千万不要低估皇帝的力量...
Do not underestimate the powers of the emperor...
不然你会落得和你父亲一样的命运
or suffer your father's fate you will.
等我死去了...
When gone am I...
你将是最后一个绝地武士
the last of the Jedi will you be.
你们家族的人对于原力都很有天份
The Force runs strong in your family.
把你所学的传于后世
Pass on what you have learned.
那就将会有...
There is...
另一个...
another...
天行者
Skywalker.
我没法办到  R2
I can't do it, R2.
我无法独自前行
I can't go on alone.
尤达永远与你同在
Yoda will always be with you.
欧比·旺
Obi-Wan.
你为什么不告诉我?
Why didn't you tell me?
你对我说维德背叛和谋杀了我的父亲
You told me Vader betrayed and murdered my father.
你的父亲被"原力"的黑暗面所吸引
Your father was seduced by the dark side of the Force.
然后他就不再是天行者安纳金  而变成了达斯·维德
He ceased to be Anakin Skywalker and became Darth Vader.
当此事发生之时...
When that happened...
那个曾经是好人的你的父亲就被毁灭了
the good man who was your father was destroyed.
所以从某种角度来说
So what I told you was true...
我告诉你的是事实
from a certain point of view.
某种角度?
A certain point of view?
卢克  你将会发现  我们坚信的很多事实
Luke, you're going to find that many of the truths we cling to...
极大程度上都源于我们自己看问题的角度
depend greatly on our own point of view.
安纳金是一个好朋友
Anakin was a good friend.
当我第一次见到他时...
When I first knew him...
你父亲已经是一个伟大的飞行员...
your father was already a great pilot...
但我对于他身上的"原力"那么强大无比惊讶
but I was amazed how strongly the Force was with him.
于是我亲自把他训练成为一名绝地武士
I took it upon myself to train him as a Jedi.
我以为我可以把他教导的如同尤达一样好
I thought that I could instruct him just as well as Yoda.
但是我错了
I was wrong.
他身上还有善良存在
There is still good in him.
他现在更多的是一部机器  而不是人
He's more machine now than man...
他扭曲而邪恶
twisted and evil.
我办不到  本
I can't do it, Ben.
你不能逃避你自己的命运
You cannot escape your destiny.
你一定要再次面对达斯·维德
You must face Darth Vader again.
我不能杀掉自己的亲生父亲
I can't kill my own father.
那皇帝已经赢了
Then the emperor has already won.
你是我们唯一的希望了
You were our only hope.
尤达提到了另外一个
Yoda spoke of another.
他提到的另外一个是你的孪生姐妹
The other he spoke of is your twin sister.
但是我没有姐妹
But I have no sister.
为了保护你们不受皇帝的迫害
To protect you both from the emperor...
你们一出生  就瞒住了你父亲
you were hidden from your father when you were born.
如同我一样  皇帝也知道
The emperor knew, as I did...
如果安纳金有任何后代
if Anakin were to have any offspring...
他们将成为对他的威胁
they would be a threat to him.
这就是为什么你的姐妹要安全的匿名生活
That is the reason why your sister remains safely anonymous.
- 莉娅是我的姐妹 - 你的直觉很准确
- Leia is my sister. - Your insight serves you well.
把你的感情埋在心底吧  卢克
Bury your feelings deep down, Luke.
它们会为你服务
They do you credit...
但是它们也会为帝国皇帝所利用
but they could be made to serve the emperor.
看看你啊  成了将军了  啊?
Look at you. A general, huh?
肯定有人告诉他们我在塔纳战役中的杰出表现了
Someone must have told them about my manoeuvre at the Battle of Tanaab.
别看我啊  朋友  我只是和他们说你是个不错的飞行员而已
Don't look at me, pal. I just said you were a fair pilot.
我不知道他们是要找人来指挥这个疯狂攻击的
I didn't know they were looking for somebody to lead this crazy attack.
我只是很奇怪他们没有让你来做这事
I'm surprised they didn't ask you to do it.
谁说他们没有  只是我没有那么疯狂而已
Who says they didn't? But I ain't crazy.
你可是名人啊  记得吗?
You're the respectable one, remember?
皇帝犯了一个重大错误  现在轮到我们攻击了
The emperor's made a critical error and the time for our attack has come.
伯森间谍们给我提供的数据标明了...
The data brought to us by the Bothan spies pinpoint the exact location...
帝国新战斗基地的准确位置
of the emperor's new battle station.
我们同时得知死星上的...
We also know that the weapon systems...
武器系统还不能正常工作
of this Death Star are not yet operational.
而整个帝国舰队散布于银河之中
With the imperial fleet spread throughout the galaxy...
徒劳的寻找我们
in a vain effort to engage us...
因此它现在基本上是不设防的
it is relatively unprotected.
而最关键的是...
But most important of all...
我们得知皇帝本人...
we've learned that the emperor himself...
现在正在亲自视察...
is personally overseeing the final stages...
死星建造的最后阶段
of the construction of this Death Star.
为了给我们提供这个消息  很多伯森人牺牲了
Many Bothans died to bring us this information.
阿克巴司令  请
Admiral Ackbar, please.
你们这里看到的就是死星围绕恩多星的布满森林的卫星旋转
You can see here the Death Star orbiting the forest moon of Endor.
尽管死星上的武器系统还不能正常工作
Although the weapon systems on this Death Star are not yet operational...
死星本身还是有很强的防御机制
the Death Star does have a strong defence mechanism.
它被一层能量盾保护着
It is protected by an energy shield...
而这个能量盾是在恩多的那颗卫星上产生的
which is generated from the nearby forest moon of Endor.
在我们尝试任何攻击之前  护盾必须要被解除
The shield must be deactivated if any attack is to be attempted.
一旦护盾被解除  我们的巡洋舰将建立一道环行防线...
Once the shield is down, our cruisers will create a perimeter...
而战斗机将飞进这个超级建筑
while the fighters fly into the superstructure...
试图摧毁主反应堆
and attempt to knock out the main reactor.
卡尔瑞辛将军自愿指挥战斗机的攻击
General Calrissian has volunteered to lead the fighter attack.
祝好运
Good luck.
你会需要好运的
You're gonna need it.
麦迪恩将军
General Madine.
我们偷了一艘帝国的小型飞船
We have stolen a small imperial shuttle.
把它假扮成一艘运输船  然后使用一个秘密的帝国密码...
Disguised as a cargo ship and using a secret imperial code...
我们可以把一队攻击部队运到卫星上去解除护盾的发生器
a strike team will land on the moon and deactivate the shield generator.
听起来很危险
Sounds dangerous.
我在猜他们会找谁接这个苦活
Wonder who they found to pull that off.
索罗将军  你的攻击部队召集完毕了吗?
General Solo, is your strike team assembled?
我的队伍做好准备了  但是我缺乏飞船的指挥人员
My team's ready. I don't have a command crew for the shuttle.
这会很难的  我不想提起你
It's gonna be rough. I didn't wanna speak for you.
- 好吧  你算一个 - 将军  算我一个
- That's one. - General, count me in.
我也去
I'm with you too.
- 怎么了? - 以后再问我
- What is it? - Ask me again sometime.
- 卢克 - 嗨  汉  楚伊
Hi, Han, Chewie.
"振奋人心"这样的词也无法表达此情此景
"Exciting" is hardly the word I would choose.
听着  我希望你乘她去
Look, I want you to take her.
我是说真的  乘她去
I mean it. Take her.
你会拥有的所需的一切
You need all the help you can get.
她可是舰队里面最快的飞船
She's the fastest ship in the fleet.
好啦  老朋友
All right, old buddy.
我知道她对你意味着什么
I know what she means to you.
我会好好照顾她的  她连个划痕都不会有
I'll take good care of her. She won't get a scratch.
怎么样?
All right?
好吧
Right.
你可是向我保证了  一个划痕都不会有
I got your promise. Not a scratch.
你可以出发了吧  海盗先生?
Would you get going, you pirate?
祝好运
Good luck.
你也一样
You too.
- 预热了吗? - 是的  她做好准备了
- Got her warmed? - Yeah, she's coming up.
我估计帝国设计她的时候没考虑到会有伍基人会乘坐的  楚伊
I don't think the Empire had Wookiees in mind when they designed her, Chewie.
嘿  你清醒着吗?
Hey, you awake?
是的  我只是有种很奇怪的感觉  好像我再也见不到她了
Yeah. I just got a funny feeling, like I'm not gonna see her again.
来吧  将军  我们开始吧
Come on, General. Let's move.
好的  楚伊  让我们看看这堆垃圾能干什么
Right. Chewie, let's see what this piece of junk can do.
- 大家都准备好了吗? - 都好了
- Ready, everybody? - All set.
那我们又上路了
Here we go again.
好了  坚持住
All right, hang on.
请问圣意如何?我的主人?
What is thy bidding, my master?
派遣舰队去恩多星系的远端
Send the fleet to the far side of Endor.
让他们在那里待命
There it will stay until called for.
那对于反叛军在索拉斯特星系附近大规模活动的报告怎么处理?
What of the reports of the rebel fleet massing near Sullust?
这无关紧要
It is of no concern.
很快反叛军就会被扑灭  而年轻的天行者会成为我们之中的一员
Soon the rebellion will be crushed and young Skywalker will be one of us.
你在这里的任务已经完成了  我的朋友
Your work here is finished, my friend.
去指挥舰上等待我的命令
Go out to the command ship and await my orders.
遵命  我的主人
Yes, my master.
要是这招不灵  我们得赶快跑路
If they don't go for this, we're gonna have to get out pretty quick.
贵机已经出现在我们的屏幕上了  请证实你们的身份
We have you on our screen now. Please identify.
泰德瑞姆号小型飞船请求解除偏导护盾
Shuttle Tydirium requesting deactivation of the deflector shield.
泰德瑞姆号  请发送解除护盾的通行密码
Shuttle Tydirium, transmit the clearance code for shield passage.
正在发送中
Transmission commencing.
现在我们就会知道这密码值不值得我们付出那么大代价了
Now we find out if that code is worth the price we paid.
会有效的
It'll work. It'll work.
维德在那艘船上
Vader's on that ship.
卢克  别那么神经过敏
Don't get jittery, Luke.
有好多指挥船呢
There are a lot of command ships.
保持距离  楚伊  但是别让他们发现你在保持距离
Keep your distance, Chewie, but don't look like you're keeping your distance.
我怎么知道怎么办  就正常飞好啦
I don't know. Fly casual.
这艘飞船要去哪里?
Where is that shuttle going?
泰德瑞姆号  你上面装了什么  你的目的地是哪里?
Shuttle Tydirium, what is your cargo and destination?
森林卫星需要的零件和技术人员
Parts and technical crew for the forest moon.
他们有通行密码吗?
Do they have a code clearance?
是个老密码了  长官  不过是对的
It's an older code, sir, but it checks out.
我准备让他们通过
I was about to clear them.
我不该来的  我来了会让这个任务更难完成
I'm endangering the mission. I shouldn't have come.
这只是你的想像而已  孩子
It's your imagination, kid.
怎么回事啊  让我们乐观点不好吗!
Come on. Let's keep a little optimism here.
要我抓住他们吗?
Shall I hold them?
不  让他们来吧
No. Leave them to me.
我会亲自处理他们
I will deal with them myself.
如您所愿  大人  继续吧
As you wish, my lord. Carry on.
他们放我们过去了  楚伊
They're not going for it, Chewie.
泰德瑞姆号
Shuttle Tydirium...
护盾马上就会解除
deactivation of the shield will commence immediately.
保持你们的航线
Follow your present course.
看  我告诉你们会成功的吧
Okay. I told you it was gonna work.
什么问题都没有
No problem.
我告诉你们这里很危险吧
I told you it was dangerous here.
- 要不我们绕一下路怎么样? - 太花时间了
- Should we try and go around? - It'll take time.
要是让他们看到我们  我们整队人就白来一趟了
This whole party will be for nothing if they see us.
楚伊和我会处理这问题的  你待这里别动
Chewie and I will take care of this. You stay here.
要安静点  那边可能有更多敌人
Quietly. There might be more of them out there.
嘿...
Hey...
连我都不相信吗
it's me.
去叫支援!快去!
Go for help! Go!
太棒了  上啊!
Great. Come on!
那边!还有两个敌人
Over there! Two more of them.
我看到他们了  等着  莉娅!
I see them. Wait. Leia!
嘿  等等!
Hey, wait!
快  阻塞他们的通讯频道  用中间那个开关
Quick, jam their comlink. Centre switch.
靠近点
Move closer.
到他侧面去贴住他
Get alongside that one.
你继续追这个家伙  我去对付那两个
Keep on that one. I'll take these two.
索罗将军  有人来了
General Solo, somebody's coming.
莉娅在哪?
Where's Leia?
- 她还没回来? - 我还以为她和你在一起呢
- She didn't come back? - I thought she was with you.
我们分开了  我们最好去找找她
We got separated. We better go look for her.
你带小队继续前进  我们三点整在护盾发生器旁边会合
Take the squad ahead. We'll meet at the shield generator at 03:00.
快点  R2  我们需要你的扫描器
Come on, R2. We'll need your scanners.
别担心  卢克主人  我们知道该怎么办
Don't worry, Master Luke. We know what to do.
你还说这里很美
And you said it was pretty here.
别再碰我了
Cut it out.
我不会伤害你的
I'm not gonna hurt you.
看来我是困在这里了
Well, looks like I'm stuck here.
糟糕的是  我都不知道这是哪里
Trouble is, I don't know where here is.
也许你可以帮我
Maybe you can help me.
来吧  坐这里
Come on. Sit down.
我保证我决不伤害你  快过来啊
I promise I won't hurt you. Now come here.
好吧  想吃点什么吗?
All right. You want something to eat?
乖
That's right.
来啊
Come on.
看  只是顶头盔
Look. It's a hat.
不会弄伤你的  来看看啊
It's not gonna hurt you. Look.
你这个小家伙神经真过敏啊  是吧?
You're a jittery little thing, aren't you?
是什么?
What is it?
别动
Freeze!
快点  起来
Come on. Get up.
- 去拿你的车  把她带回基地 - 遵命
- Get your ride. Take her back to base. - Yes, sir.
怎么...?
What the-
快  我们离开这里
Come on. Let's get out of here.
我告诉过你  让你待在指挥船上
I told you to remain on the command ship.
一小队反抗军穿过了护盾  在恩多着陆了
A small rebel force has penetrated the shield and landed on Endor.
是啊  我知道
Yes, I know.
我儿子和他们在一起
My son is with them.
- 你肯定吗? - 我已经感觉到他了  我的主人
- Are you sure? - I have felt him, my master.
真奇怪  我还没有感觉到
Strange that I have not.
你对此事的感觉清楚无误吗  维德勋爵
I wonder if your feelings on this matter are clear, Lord Vader.
很清楚  我的主人
They are clear, my master.
那你就要去那颗守护卫星等他
Then you must go to the sanctuary moon and wait for him.
他会来找我吗?
He will come to me?
是的  我已经预见到了
I have foreseen it.
他对你的同情心会让他万劫不复
His compassion for you will be his undoing.
他会找到你  然后你要带他来见我
He will come to you, and then you will bring him before me.
谨遵圣意
As you wish.
卢克主人
Master Luke.
那边还有两台毁掉的飞车
There's two more wrecked speeders back there.
而且我还找到了这个
And I found this.
恐怕R2的传感器找不到任何莉娅公主的踪迹
I'm afraid that R2's sensors can find no trace of Princess Leia.
我希望她一切平安
I hope she's all right.
什么事  楚伊?
What, Chewie?
我不懂  不过是只死兽而已  有什么好看的
I don't get it. It's just a dead animal.
楚伊  等下  别碰!
Chewie, wait! Don't!
干的漂亮
Nice work.
干的真棒  楚伊
Great, Chewie.
太漂亮了  你总是用胃来思考的吗?
Great. Always thinking with your stomach.
别抱怨了  我们还是来想想怎么出去吧
Take it easy. Let's just figure a way to get out of this thing.
汉  你能够碰到我的光剑吗?
Han, can you reach my lightsabre?
当然可以
Yeah. Sure.
R2  我不知道这是不是个好主意
R2, I'm not sure that's such a good idea.
从这么高掉下去!
It's a very long drop!
嘿  别用那玩意指着我
Hey. Point that thing someplace else.
嘿!
Hey!
汉  别这样  没事的
Han, don't. It'll be all right.
楚伊  把你的弩给他们
Chewie, give them your crossbow.
哦  我的头
Oh, my head.
哦  天啊
Oh, my goodness.
你懂得他们在说什么吗?
Do you understand anything they're saying?
哦  是的  卢克主人
Oh, yes, Master Luke.
要知道我可是通晓超过六百万种...
Remember that I am fluent in over six million forms-
你对他们说什么了?
What are you telling them?
我觉得我说的是"你好"
"Hello," I think.
不过我也可能搞错了... 他们用的是一种很原始的语言...
I could be mistaken... they're using a very primitive dialect...
但是我相信他们认为我是什么神
but I do believe they think I am some sort of god.
那你干嘛不对他们显示点神力  让我们离开这里呢?
Why don't you use your divine influence and get us out of this?
对不起  索罗将军  但是这样做是不合适的
I beg your pardon, General Solo, but that just wouldn't be proper.
合适?
Proper?
我的程序不允许我假装成神祉
It's against my programming to impersonate a deity.
为什么  你...
Why, you-
我的错  请原谅
My mistake.
他是我的老朋友了
He's an old friend of mine.
嘿
Hey.
我对此感觉很不好
I have a really bad feeling about this.
他说什么?
What did he say?
这么说真让我尴尬  索罗将军...
I'm rather embarrassed, General Solo...
但是看起来你好像是为我举办宴会的主菜
but it appears you are to be the main course at a banquet in my honour.
殿下
Your Royal Highness.
这些人是我的朋友
These are my friends.
3PO  告诉他们必须要释放他们
不知怎么我感觉这好像没起什么作用
Somehow I got the feeling that didn't help us very much.
3PO  告诉他们如果他们不按你说的做...
你会非常生气  并且会使用你的神力
you'll become angry and use your magic.
但是  卢克主人  什么神力?我根本就不会什么...
But, Master Luke, what magic? I couldn't possibly...
就这么对他们说
Tell them.
你看到没  卢克主人?他们不相信我...
You see, Master Luke? They didn't believe me...
就如同我说的一样
just as I said they wouldn't.
等等
Wait.
怎么回事?
What's happening?
放我下来  救命啊!
Put me down! Help!
谁放我下来啊!
Somebody!
救命啊!
Somebody help!
卢克主人!R2  快救救我!
Master Luke! R2, quickly!
谢天谢地
Thank goodness.
谢谢你  3PO
Thanks, 3PO.
我从来不知道我有这种能力
I never knew I had it in me.
...塔图因...
...Tatooine...
莉娅公主... R2
Princess Leia... R2.
...达斯·维德!
...Darth Vader!
...死星
...Death Star.
...绝地武士...  欧比·旺·科努比
...Jedi... Obi-Wan Kenobi.
好啦  R2  我马上就要说到这个了
Yes, R2, I was just coming to that.
卢克主人...
Master Luke...
...千年鹰号...云雾城
...Millennium Falcon... Cloud City.
...维德!
...Vader!
汉·索罗...
Han Solo...
...碳化
...carbon.
...沙列克
...Sarlacc.
- 怎么回事? - 我不知道
- What's going on? - I don't know.
太好了  我们现在是部落的一份子了
Wonderful. We are now a part of the tribe.
我早就等着这一天了
Just what I always wanted.
帮点忙也比不帮忙好啊  楚伊
Short help's better than no help at all, Chewie.
侦察兵们会告诉我们通向护盾发生器最快的路在哪
The scouts will show us the quickest way to the shield generator.
太好了  有多远?
Good. How far is it?
问他
Ask him.
对了  我们还需要些补给
We need some fresh supplies too.
还有  最好能把我们的武器要回来
Try and get our weapons back.
快点  我们时间不多了
Hurry up. I haven't got all day.
卢克  怎么了?
Luke, what's wrong?
莉娅  你记得你的母亲吗?
Leia, do you remember your mother-
你真正的母亲?
your real mother?
只记得一点了  我很小的时候她就去世了
Just a little bit. She died when I was very young.
你还记得什么?
What do you remember?
只有一点印象了  还有感觉
Just images really. Feelings.
告诉我
Tell me.
她...非常美
She was... very beautiful.
很善良...但是也很忧伤
Kind... but sad.
你干嘛问我这个?
Why are you asking me this?
我一点都不记得我母亲了
I have no memory of my mother.
我从来没有见过她
I never knew her.
卢克  告诉我  什么让你这么忧心忡忡?
Luke, tell me. What's troubling you?
维德在这里  就是现在  就在这颗卫星上
Vader is here. Now. On this moon.
你怎么知道?
How do you know?
我感觉到他的存在了
I felt his presence.
他来找我了  如果我离他足够近他就能感觉到
He's come for me. He can feel when I'm near.
这就是我为什么必须离开
That's why I have to go.
只要我待在这里  我就会危害到整组人的安全
As long as I stay, I'm endangering the group
也会影响任务的完成
and our mission here.
- 我必须要面对他 - 为什么?
- I have to face him. - Why?
他是我的父亲
He's my father.
你的父亲?
Your father?
还有其他的事  你可能听起来很难接受  但是你必须要接受
There's more. It won't be easy for you to hear it, but you must.
如果我回不来的话  你就是同盟军的唯一希望了
If I don't make it back, you're the only hope for the Alliance.
别这么说
Don't talk that way.
我无法理解你的能力  永远无法理解
You have a power I don't understand and could never have.
你错了  莉娅
You're wrong, Leia.
你也有同样的力量
You have that power too.
等时间到了  你会和我一样学会使用这种力量
In time, you'll learn to use it as I have.
"原力"在我的家族中都很强
The Force is strong in my family.
我的父亲拥有它
My father has it.
我拥有它
I have it.
还有...
And...
我的姐妹也拥有它
my sister has it.
是的  就是你  莉娅
Yes. It's you, Leia.
我知道
I know.
不知道怎么回事...
Somehow...
我一直能体会到这些
I've always known.
那你就知道为什么我必须要面对他
Then you know why I have to face him.
卢克  跑吧  跑远远的
Luke, run away. Far away.
如果他能感觉到你的存在  就离开这个地方
If he can feel your presence, then leave this place.
- 我多希望我能和你一起去啊 - 不  你不能去
- I wish I could go with you. - No, you don't.
你一直都很坚强
You've always been strong.
但是为什么你必须要面对他?
But why must you confront him?
因为他的心中还有善良  我可以感觉到
Because there is good in him. I've felt it.
他不会把我转变到皇帝那边去.
He won't turn me over to the emperor.
相反的  我可以拯救他  把他转变到正义的这边来
I can save him. I can turn him back to the good side.
我必须要试试
I have to try.
嘿  你们在干嘛?
Hey, what's going on?
没什么  我只是想单独待一会儿
Nothing. I just wanna be alone for a little while.
没什么?
Nothing?
告诉我  怎么了?
Tell me. What's going on?
我不能告诉你
I can't tell you.
那你能对卢克说?你只能对他说吗?
Could you tell Luke? Is that who you could tell?
对不起
I'm sorry.
抱着我
Hold me.
这是投降的反叛军
This is the rebel that surrendered.
尽管他否认  我还是相信还有更多他们的人
Although he denies it, I believe there may be more of them...
我请求批准对这一地区作进一步搜索
and I request permission to conduct a further search of the area.
他身上的武器只有这个
He was armed only with this.
干的很好  指挥官阁下
Good work, Commander.
你可以离开了
Leave us.
进行搜索  把他的同伴抓来
Conduct your search and bring his companions to me.
遵命  大人
Yes, my lord.
皇帝陛下一直在等你
The emperor has been expecting you.
我知道  父亲
I know, Father.
就是说  你已经接受了事实了
So, you have accepted the truth.
我接受的事实是你曾经是天行者安纳金  父亲
I've accepted the truth that you were once Anakin Skywalker, my father.
那个名字对我已经没有任何意义了
That name no longer has any meaning for me.
那名字代表的才是真正的你  你只是忘了而已
It is the name of your true self. You've only forgotten.
我知道你心中还有善意
I know there is good in you.
皇帝没有从你心中全部夺走它
The emperor hasn't driven it from you fully.
这就是为什么你以前没有杀害我
That was why you couldn't destroy me.
这就是为什么你现在不会带我去见你的皇帝
That's why you won't bring me to your emperor now.
看来你又制造了一柄新的光剑啊
I see you have constructed a new lightsabre.
你的技巧已经尽善尽美了
Your skills are complete.
你确实很强大  如同皇帝预见的一样
Indeed you are powerful, as the emperor has foreseen.
跟我来
Come with me.
欧比·旺以前也这么想
Obi-Wan once thought as you do.
但是你不知道黑暗的力量有多强
You don't know the power of the dark side.
我必须服从我的主人
I must obey my master.
我不会投入你的一方的  你只能被迫杀了我
I will not turn, and you'll be forced to kill me.
如果这是你的命运的话
If that is your destiny.
仔细感觉一下  父亲  你怎么能这么做
Search your feelings, Father. You can't do this.
我能感觉到你心中的矛盾  放开你心中的仇恨吧
I feel the conflict within you. Let go of your hate.
太晚了  儿子
It is too late for me, son.
皇帝陛下会向你展示"原力"的真实本质
The emperor will show you the true nature of the Force.
他现在是你的主人了
He is your master now.
那我父亲就真的是死了
Then my father is truly dead.
控制堡的主入口...
The main entrance to the control bunker...
就在那着陆平台的另一端
is on the far side of that landing platform.
- 这任务不容易 - 别担心
- This isn't gonna be easy. - Don't worry.
楚伊和我去过很多比这更防卫森严的地方
Chewie and me got into a lot of places more heavily guarded than this.
他说什么?
What's he saying?
他说有一条秘密通道通向山脊的另一侧
He says there's a secret entrance on the other side of the ridge.
司令官  我们已经就位了  所有战机都准备好了
Admiral, we're in position. All fighters accounted for.
准备倒数计时
Proceed with the countdown.
所有部队准备进入攻击坐标
All groups assume attack coordinates.
别担心  我的朋友在下面
Don't worry. My friend's down there.
他会按时解除护盾的
He'll have that shield down on time.
要不然这就是历时最短的攻击了
Or this'll be the shortest offensive of all time.
所有飞船  按我命令  准备进行超空间跳跃
All craft, prepare to jump into hyperspace on my mark.
好  准备
All right. Stand by.
后门  是吧?这主意不错
Back door, huh? Good idea.
只有几个警卫  应该不怎么困难
It's only a few guards. This shouldn't be too much trouble.
只要一个人发现就足以拉响警报了
It only takes one to sound the alarm.
那我们就无声无息的把他们干掉
Then we'll do it real quiet-like.
- 哦  天啊  莉娅公主 - 安静
- Oh, my. Princess Leia. - Quiet.
我恐怕我们的毛绒同伴...
I'm afraid our furry companion...
已经跑过去做什么冒失的举动了
has gone and done something rather rash.
突然袭击没戏了
There goes our surprise attack.
看  那里!抓住他!
Look, over there! Stop him!
这小毛球干的还真不错  就剩一个了
Not bad for a little furball. There's only one left.
你待在这里  我们会解决掉他的
You stay here. We'll take care of this.
我决定我们应该待在此处
I have decided that we shall stay here.
嘿!
Hey!
欢迎啊  年轻的天行者
Welcome, young Skywalker.
我等你多时了
I have been expecting you.
你再也不需要那些了
You'll no longer need those.
警卫  你可以退下了
Guards, leave us.
我正期待着完成你的训练呢
I'm looking forward to completing your training.
到时  你就会承认我是你的主人了
In time, you will call me master.
那你就大错特错了
You're gravely mistaken.
你无法像对我父亲一样转变我
You won't convert me as you did my father.
哦  不  年轻的绝地武士
Oh, no, my young Jedi.
你会发现错的是你...
You will find that it is you who are mistaken...
而且你对于很多事情理解都是错的
about a great many things.
这是他的光剑
His lightsabre.
啊  没错  绝地武士的武器
Ah, yes. AJedi's weapon.
和你父亲的差不多
Much like your father's.
但是你要知道你父亲再也无法脱离黑暗一方了
By now you must know your father can never be turned from the dark side.
而你也将如此
So will it be with you.
你错了
You're wrong.
很快我就会死去...而你会和我一起死去
Soon I'll be dead- and you with me.
也许你说的是你们反叛舰队马上要进行的攻击吧
Perhaps you refer to the imminent attack of your rebel fleet.
没错吧
Yes.
我向你保证我们待在这里是非常安全的
I assure you we are quite safe from your friends here.
你的过于自信正是你的弱点
Your overconfidence is your weakness.
你对于你朋友的迷信则是你的弱点
Your faith in your friends is yours.
反抗是无意义的  儿子
It is pointless to resist, my son.
已经发生的一切都是按我的剧本在进行
Everything that has transpired has done so according to my design.
你在守护卫星上的那群朋友
Your friends up there on the sanctuary moon...
正在迈进一个陷阱  你们的反抗舰队也一样
are walking into a trap, as is your rebel fleet.
是我允许同盟军...
It was I who allowed the Alliance...
知道护盾发生器的地点的
to know the location of the shield generator.
你们那一小群可怜的家伙对它是无法撼动分毫的
It is quite safe from your pitiful little band.
一群我最好的部队正在等待着他们呢
An entire legion of my best troops awaits them.
恐怕偏导护盾...
I'm afraid the deflector shield...
到你朋友来的时候还会工作的很正常呢!
will be quite operational when your friends arrive.
好啦!
All right!
起来!走开!
Up! Move!
快点  快点
Quickly. Quickly.
汉  快点
Han, hurry.
舰队马上就要来了
The fleet will be here any moment.
冲啊  上啊!
Charges. Come on. Come on!
哦  天啊  他们会被抓的
Oh, my. They'll be captured.
等等!回来!
Wait! Come back!
R2  和我待在一起
R2, stay with me.
别动!
Freeze!
你们这群反叛的混蛋
You rebel scum.
- 所有部门向我报告 - 红色长机待命
- All wings report in. - Red Leader standing by.
- 灰色长机待命 - 绿色长机待命
- Grey Leader standing by. - Green Leader standing by.
将S型叶片锁定在攻击位置上
Lock S-foils in attack positions.
愿"原力"与我们同在!
May the Force be with us.
我们马上就能知道这个护盾究竟是不是解除了
We've gotta be able to get a reading on that shield- up or down.
如果他们不知道我们会来
How could they be jamming us if they don't know-
他们怎么会干扰我们的通信
if we're coming.
放弃进攻  护盾仍然在工作
Break off the attack. The shield is still up.
我没有收到任何探测数据  你肯定吗?
I get no reading. You sure?
拉起!所有飞船拉起!
Pull up! All craft pull up!
进行规避动作  绿色编队  紧密控制MV-7地区
Take evasive action. Green Group, stick close to Holding Sector MV-7.
司令官  47区发现敌舰
Admiral, we have enemy ships in Sector 47.
这是个陷阱
It's a trap.
战机逼近
Fighters coming in.
他们数量太多了
There's too many.
加速至战斗速度  吸引他们的火力  不要让他们射击巡洋舰
Accelerate to attack speed. Draw their fire away from the cruisers.
金色长机  遵命
Copy, Gold Leader.
来吧  孩子
Come, boy.
自己看看
See for yourself.
从这里  你将见证到同盟军的最后毁灭
From here, you will witness the final destruction of the Alliance...
和你们那无关痛痒的反叛的最后终结
and the end of your insignificant rebellion.
你想要这个
You want this...
对吧?
don't you?
你胸中的仇恨正越来越强
The hate is swelling in you now.
拿起你的绝地武器吧
Take your Jedi weapon.
用他来杀我
Use it.
我现在手无存铁
I am unarmed.
用他把我击倒吧
Strike me down with it.
屈服于你的愤怒
Give in to your anger.
每一刻  你都将逐渐变成我的仆人
With each passing moment you make yourself more my servant.
这是无可避免的
It is unavoidable.
这是你命中注定的
It is your destiny.
你  和你父亲一样...
You, like your father...
现在...
are now...
都是我的了
mine.
好啦  快走啊
All right, move it.
喂  我说  那边的
Hello. I say, over there.
你们在找我吗?
Were you looking for me?
把那两个家伙抓过来
Bring those two down here.
他们过来了  R2  你肯定这是个好主意吗?
They're on their way. R2, are you sure this was a good idea?
站住
Freeze.
别动
Don't move.
我们投降
We surrender.
密码已经变了
The code's changed.
- 我们需要R2 - 终端在这里
- We need R2. - Here's the terminal.
R2  你在哪里?
R2, where are you?
到地堡这里来  我们需要你
We need you at the bunker right away.
走?你什么意思?
Going? What do you mean?
去哪里啊  R2?
Going where, R2?
等等  R2  这可不是逞英雄的时候
Wait. R2, this is no time for heroics.
回来!
Come back!
小心  威治  有三架从你头顶方向来了
Watch yourself, Wedge. Three from above.
- 红色三号  红色二号  靠近我 - 明白
- Red Three, Red Two, pull in. - Got it.
三架敌机逼近  角度20度
Three of them coming in, 20 degrees.
向左急转  我对付长机
Cut left. I'll take the leader.
他们正飞向医疗舰
They're heading for the medical frigate.
气压稳定
Pressure's steady.
只有战斗机在攻击  灭星者在等什么?
Only the fighters are attacking. What are the Stardestroyers waiting for?
长官!我们已经就位  准备攻击!
We're in attack position, sir.
- 就地等待 - 我们不进攻吗  长官?
- Hold here. - We're not going to attack?
我的命令是陛下亲自下的  他有特殊计划
My orders are from the emperor himself. He has something special planned.
我们只要防止他们逃跑即可
We only need to keep them from escaping.
如你所见  年轻的学徒
As you can see, my young apprentice...
你的朋友们已经失败了
your friends have failed.
现在看看这个...
Now witness the firepower...
全副武装的战斗基地的威力吧
of this fully armed and operational battle station.
指挥官  自由射击!
Fire at will, Commander.
射击
Fire.
这是从死星射出来的
That blast came from the Death Star.
那家伙可以工作
That thing's operational.
大本营一号  这是金色长机
Home 1, this is Gold Leader.
我们也见到了  所有部队准备撤退
We saw it. All craft prepare to retreat.
可是你再不会得到这么好的机会了  司令官
You won't get another chance at this, Admiral.
我们别无选择  卡尔瑞辛将军
We have no choice, General Calrissian.
我们的巡洋舰顶不住那个级别的攻击
Our cruisers can't repel firepower of that magnitude.
汉会解除那个护盾的  我们要给他更多的时间
Han will have that shield down. We've gotta give him more time.
我们来啦
We're coming.
快啊
Come on.
R2  快点!
R2, hurry!
天啊!
My goodness!
你干嘛要这么英勇?
Why did you have to be so brave?
好吧  我猜我能找到开门的线路
Well, I suppose I could hot-wire this thing.
我掩护你
I'll cover you.
是的  靠近  能有多近就有多近
Yes, I said closer. Move as close as you can...
在极近距离对灭星者进行攻击
and engage those Stardestroyers at point-blank range.
但是在那种距离我们顶不住灭星者多久的攻击
At that close range, we won't last long against those Stardestroyers.
起码比死星的攻击顶的要久
We'll last longer than we will against that Death Star...
我们说不定还能干掉一两艘
and we might take a few of them with us.
她要爆炸啦!
She's gonna blow!
我被击中了!
I'm hit!
你的舰队已经失败了
Your fleet is lost...
而你在恩多卫星上的朋友们也不可能存活
and your friends on the Endor moon will not survive.
无路可逃啦
There is no escape...
年轻的学徒
my young apprentice.
同盟即将毁灭
The Alliance will die...
你的朋友也将死去
as will your friends.
很好
Good.
我能感觉到你的愤怒
I can feel your anger.
我现在没有防护  拿起你的武器吧
I am defenceless. Take your weapon.
用你的仇恨将我击倒...
Strike me down with all of your hatred...
然后你就将彻底进入黑暗一方
and your journey towards the dark side will be complete.
- 看! - 把他从那弄走!
- Look! - Get him off of there.
我想我找到方法了
I think I got it.
我找到了
I got it!
你还好吗?
Are you all right?
- 让我看看 - 还不错
- Let's see. - It's not bad.
- 站住! - 哦  亲爱的
- Freeze! - Oh, dear.
别动
Don't move.
- 我爱你 - 我知道
- I love you. - I know.
举起手来
Hands up.
站起来
Stand up.
退后
Stay back.
下来  她受伤了
Get down here. She's wounded.
不  等一下
No, wait.
我有法子了
I got an idea.
很好
Good.
感觉你好战的心吧  孩子
Use your aggressive feelings, boy.
让仇恨充满你的全身
Let the hate flow through you.
欧比·旺把你教的不错啊
Obi-Wan has taught you well.
我不会和你作战了  父亲
I will not fight you, Father.
放下你的武器是很不明智的
You are unwise to lower your defences.
你的思想背叛了你  父亲
Your thoughts betray you, Father.
我能感觉到你内心的善良  矛盾
I feel the good in you, the conflict.
没有什么矛盾
There is no conflict.
你以前没办法让自己杀掉我...
You couldn't bring yourself to kill me before...
我不信现在你就行
and I don't believe you'll destroy me now.
你太低估黑暗的力量了
You underestimate the power of the dark side.
如果你不作战
If you will not fight...
你就会落入你注定的结局
then you will meet your destiny.
很好
Good.
- 注意  6点方向有敌机 - 金色长机  我来对付他
- Watch out. Squad at.06. - I'm on it, Gold Leader.
打的漂亮  红色二号
Good shot, Red Two.
我们现在肯定已经在其中了  汉  快点啊
We're sure in the middle of it now. Come on, Han, old buddy.
别让我们失望啊
Don't let me down.
结束了  指挥官
It's over, Commander.
反叛军已经被击溃  他们正在四散奔逃
The rebels have been routed. They're fleeing.
我们需要增援以便继续追击
We need reinforcements to continue the pursuit.
派三个班过去帮忙
Send three squads to help.
- 打开后门 - 遵命  长官
- Open the back door. - Sir.
再扔给我一颗炸弹
Throw me another charge.
你不能永远躲避  卢克
You cannot hide forever, Luke.
我不会和你作战的
I will not fight you.
来黑暗这方吧
Give yourself to the dark side.
只有这样才能救你的朋友
It is the only way you can save your friends.
就是这样
Yes.
你的思想背叛了你
Your thoughts betray you.
你对他们的感情是如此之深....
Your feelings for them are strong...
尤其是对
especially for...
你的姐妹
sister.
你有一个孪生姐妹
So you have a twin sister.
你的感觉也正在背叛她
Your feelings have now betrayed her too.
欧比·旺很聪明  把她偷偷藏起来
Obi-Wan was wise to hide her from me.
不过现在他是彻底失败了
Now his failure is complete.
如果你不愿意投入黑暗一方
If you will not turn to the dark side...
那也许她会
then perhaps she will.
不可能!
Never!
很好!
Good!
你的恨意让你强大!
Your hate has made you powerful.
现在  走完你注定要走的路...
Now, fulfil your destiny...
取代你父亲的位置  在我身边为我服务
and take your father's place at my side.
决不!
Never.
我决不会投入黑暗一方
I'll never turn to the dark side.
你失败了  皇帝陛下
You've failed, Your Highness.
我是一个绝地武士...
I am a Jedi...
如同我面前的父亲一样
like my father before me.
好吧  绝地武士
So be it, Jedi.
跑啊!
Move! Move!
护盾已经解除了  对死星主反应堆发动攻击
The shield is down. Commence attack on the Death Star's main reactor.
我们马上就去  红色编队  金色编队  所有战机跟我来
We're on our way. Red Group, Gold Group, all fighters follow me.
我告诉过你他们一定能办到
I told you they'd do it.
如果你不愿投入我们...
If you will not be turned...
你就会被消灭
you will be destroyed.
年轻的傻瓜
Young fool.
现在  到了这最后时刻
Only now, at the end...
你明白了吗
do you understand.
你那点微末功夫根本无法和黑暗的力量相提并论
Your feeble skills are no match for the power of the dark side.
你太没眼光了  你会为此付出代价的
You have paid the price for your lack of vision.
父亲  救我!
Father, please!
现在  年轻的天行者...
Now, young Skywalker...
你将死去
you will die.
我要上了
I'm going in.
这什么都没有
Here goes nothing.
去最强的火力区  能源发生器一定在那里
Lock onto the strongest power source. It should be the power generator.
保持编队  小心驾驶  我们可能很快就没有足够空间了
Form up. Stay alert. We could run out of space real fast.
分开  飞回到表面去
Split up and head back to the surface.
看看你能不能吸引一些敌机跟住你
See if you can get a few of those TIE fighters to follow you.
遵命  金色长机
Copy, Gold Leader.
太近了
That was too close.
我们得给那些战机更多时间
We've got to give those fighters more time.
击中火力射击超级灭星者
Concentrate all fire on that Super Stardestroyer.
长官  舰桥的偏导护盾已经失效了
Sir, we've lost our bridge deflector shields.
增加前方火力  我不希望任何东西穿过来
Intensify the forward batteries. I don't want anything to get through.
增加前方火力!
Intensify forward firepower!
太晚了!
Too late!
帮我把这个面具取下来
Help me take this mask off.
但是这样你会死的
But you'll die.
现在没有什么能救我了
Nothing can stop that now.
但是起码
Just for once...
让我能
let me...
亲眼看你一次
look on you with my own eyes.
好  走吧  儿子
Now go, my son.
别管我了
Leave me.
不  我要带你一起走
No. You're coming with me.
我不会留你在这里的  我要救活你
I'll not leave you here. I've got to save you.
你已经救了我了  卢克
You already have, Luke.
你是对的
You were right.
你对我的看法是对的
You were right about me.
告诉你的姐妹
Tell your sister...
你是对的
you were right.
父亲
Father.
我不会离开你
I won't leave you.
就是这了
There it is.
威治  去干掉北塔上的能源稳定器
Wedge, go for the power regulator on the north tower.
遵命  金色长机  我马上就去
Copy, Gold Leader. I'm already on my way out.
让舰队远离死星
Move the fleet away from the Death Star.
他们成功了
They did it!
我肯定那东西爆炸的时候卢克不在上面
I'm sure Luke wasn't on that thing when it blew.
他不在
He wasn't.
我能感觉到
I can feel it.
你爱她
You love him.
对吧?
Don't you?
是的
Yes.
好吧  我能理解
All right. I understand.
很好
Fine.
等他回来以后...
When he comes back...
我不会挡你们的路
I won't get in the way.
不是你想的那样的
It's not like that at all.
他是我的兄弟
He's my brother.
威萨自由了!
Wesa free!